Guide to the William Nelson Parker Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1951-1992; Accession 1993-M-086; 2 linear feet (3 boxes)
  - Writings
    - Review of Kimmel, L. H., State and Local Finance: A Historical Study (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "An Interpretation of Economics 1-2 in Terms of Cultural Relativism," Economics faculty of Williams College, on discussing alternative for the elementary course. unpublished, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Seminar notes. Seminar on the Scope of Economic History, given at Yale University. unpublished, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Brief Notes on the Direction of Future Work in Economic History. unpublished, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Henry Varnum Poor", 1956 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Comments on Dr. Adler's paper. Ann Arbor Conference. unpublished, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Comments on Prof. Kindleberger's Paper. Ann Arbor conference of Resources & Economic Growth. unpublished, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Comments. Response to papers presented by Alfred Chandler and Beatrice Newcomer at AAAS meeting in Pittsburgh. unpublished, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Seminar notes on the Scope of Economic History. Prof. Gerchenkron's seminar at Harvard. unpublished, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Memorandum. Preservation and Use of Nineteenth Century Census Records. unpublished, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Letter to Prof. Moses Abramovitz, Stanford University, Sept. 15, 1967. Remarks on "slavery "session of E.H.A. conference in Philadelphia. unpublished (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "Comments by William N. Parker," at Bloomington, Indiana. unpublished, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Comments. Remarks never made in Yale College Faculty Meeting in response to student demonstrations at Wright Hall and Executive Committee disciplinary actions. unpublished, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Introduction for Douglas North. Economic History Association President's Banquet, Atlanta. unpublished, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Personal letter to Lloyd Reynolds, March 30, 1973. On the retirement from the Economics Department of Raymond Goldsmith and William Fellner. unpublished (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Discussion of Paper by Jeffrey Williamson. Conference at Austin, Texas. unpublished, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Comments to Introduce Conference. Conference on Ransom and Such, Another Kind of Freedom. unpublished, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Comments on Douglass North's Paper, "The Rise of Government Intervention in the American Economy, 1800-1914." Meeting of the American Historical Association at San Francisco. unpublished, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "Pastoral Letter from the Director of Graduate Students," University Economics Newsletter. Vol. 1, No. 1, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Remarks at the close of the Conference. US/USSR Historians' Conference, Moscow. unpublished, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "Author's Comments on the paper Historiography of the Post Bellum South," US/USSR Historians' Conference, Moscow. unpublished, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Discussion of Papers. Toronto EHA Conference. unpublished, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - "Notes for New DGS," unpublished, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Memorandum to Jiro Tokuyama, NRI, Tokyo, August 30, 1978. Some Reflections on the July Visit to Japan. unpublished (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Comment on Papers. New Orleans OAH Meetings. unpublished, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Discussion of the Sheridan and McHugh Papers. Meeting of SSHA, Rochester. unpublished, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Introductory remarks for R. A. Easterlin on the Occasion of R. A. Easterlin's Terminal Address as President of the Economic History Association, Boston. unpublished, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - "To William Nordhaus on His Fortieth Birthday," unpublished, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - "Remarks at the Retirement Dinner of Tjalling Koopmans and John Perry Miller," unpublished, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - "Sayonara," American Studies Conference, Sapporo, Japan. unpublished, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - "To New York Times regarding FCC regulations," unpublished, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "Communication Techniques and Social Organization in the World Economy," Eighth International Economic History Congress, Budapest. unpublished, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Remarks on the Occasion. The Award of the DeVane Medal to Lloyd G Reynolds, Phi Beta Kappa Dinner. unpublished, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Discussant's Remarks. Economic History Association Session on Technology & Organization, chaired by Gavin Wright, Washington, DC. unpublished, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Comment on Nancy Cott's manuscript, Feminism in Early Twentieth-Century United States. unpublished, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - "Opening Remarks to the Symposium on the 50th Anniversary of the Spanish Civil War," Symposium held at the Yale Law School. unpublished, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - "Toast to Language," The closing banquet of the US/USSR Historians' Conference on 19th-Century Agrarian History, held in Tallin, ESSR June 11, 1987. unpublished (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - "In Memory of Nancy Dunlap Ruggles," American Eonomic Association Newsletter. Spring/Summer 1987 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - "A Parting Word: Eleanor van Buren," Department party on the retirement of Eleanor van Buren. unpublished, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Letter to Michael Emerson of the EC. Response to questions regarding history of development of economic unification for Western Europe. unpublished, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - "To Jim and Betty Tobin, an Analysis and a Tribute," Departmental party held in honor of Jim and Betty Tobin at the home of Rick and Jane Levin, on the occasion of Jim's retirement, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Personal Letter. Response to Barry Katz's request for information regarding the R&A section of the OSS. unpublished, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - "Raymond W. Goldsmith (1904-1987)," Obituary of Raymond W. Goldsmith (1904-1988). Obituary for Raymond Goldsmith. Review of Income and Wealth, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Statement presented at Yale College Faculty Meeting, February 2, 1989. After the appointment of a new dean at SOM. unpublished (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Statement presented at Yale College Faculty Meeting, March 2, 1989. At the proposal of a Resolution to the Yale College Faculty after the appointment of a new dean at SOM. unpublished (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "A Watchdog for the Bulldog," Before the April 6 meeting of the Yale College Faculty, after the appointment of a new dean at SOM. Yale Daily News. Wed., April 5, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - "The Organizational Structure of International and Area Studies," Disquisition. vol. 1, no. 2, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Comments. Comments at E.H.A. Montreal Meeting, September 1990. unpublished (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Eulogy. Remarks at the memorial service of his sister, Evalyn Parker Carruthers, Ph.D., at Greenfield Hills Congregational Church, Fairfield, CT, December 31, 1990. unpublished (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - "An Interview with William N. Parker," Interview of W. N. Parker for Cliometrics Society Newsletter, conducted by Paul Rhode. Newsletter of the Cliometric Society. Vol. 6, No. 2, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - "Economic History in an Undergraduate Education," Talk to the Economics Faculty. Economics Faculty and Dana Fellows, at Mory's, April 1991. unpublished (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - "Words," a poem. unpublished, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Speech and poem. Reproduction, with slight extension, of remarks made at the celebration in honor of Martin Shubik, at the New Haven Lawn Club, April 19, 1991. unpublished (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Letter to the Editor of The New York Times Magazine. On the abrupt resignation of Benno Schmidt. The New York Times Magazine, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - "Structures for Area and International Studies in American Universities," Disquisition. vol. 2, no. 1, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Review of J. K. Galbraith, American Captialism: The Concept of Countervailing Power, unpublished, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Review of M. J. Herskovits, Economic Anthropology: A Study in Comparative Economics (New York: Knopf, 1952), unpublished, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Review of Etienne Mantoux, The Carthaginian Peace, or The Economic Consequences of Mr. Keynes (New York: Scribners' 1952), ? published or unpublished?, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Review of Fritz Redlich, The Beginnings and Development of German Business History (Bulletin of the Business Historical Society, 1952), The. Vol. XV, No. 3, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Review of Ingvar Svennilson, Growth and Stagnation in the European Economy (Geneva: E. G. E., 1954), The Scandinaviai Economic History Review, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Review of Alfred D. Chandler, Jr., Henry Varnum Poor, Business Editor, Analyst, and Reformer (Cambridge, Mass: Harvard University Press, 1956), The Southern Economic Journal. vol. 23, no. 4, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Review of Walther G. Hoffman, British Industry, 1700-1950 (Oxford: Basil Blackwell, 1955), Journal of the American Statistical Association. Vol. 51, No. 276, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Review of A. Chabert (Centre d'Etudes Economiques, Etudes et Memoires), Les salaires dans I'industrie francaise (la metallurgie) (Paris: A. Colin, 1955), The Journal of Economic History. Vol. XVII, No. 2, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Review of Pierre Bauchet, Les tableaux economiques: analyse de la region lorraine (Paris: Editions Genin, Librairie de Medicis, 1955), The Journal of Economic History. Vol XVII, No. 2, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Review of Robert J. Holloway, (Stanford, Calififornia: Stanford University Press, 1952), The Development of the Russian Iron and Steel Industry. Vol. XVII, No. 2, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Review of Ger von Klass, Krupps: The Story of an Industrial Empire (London: Sidgwick and Jackson, 1954), The Journal of Economc History. Vol. 17, No. 1, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Review of Emile Rideau, Essor et problèmes d'une région française (Paris: Editions Ouvrières 1956), The Journal of Political Economy. Vol. LXV, No. 5, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Review of Charles de Marliave, Les mines d'anthracite de la Mure, 1806-1946 (Paris and Grenoble: B. Arthaud, 1955), The J ournal of Economic History. Vol XVIII, No. 1, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Review of Heinrich Popitz, Hans Paul Bahrdt, Ernst August Jures, and Hanno Kesting, Technik and Industriearbeit: Soziologische Untersuchungen in der Hüttenindustrie (Tübingen: J. C. B. Mohr (Paul Siebeck), 1957), The Journal of Economic History. Vol. XIX, No. 2, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Review of Haskell P. Wald, Taxation of Agricultural Land in Underdeveloped Economies (Cambridge, Mass.: Harvard University Press, 1959), ? published, but where?, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Review of J. Frederic Dewhurst, John O. Coppock, P. Lamartine Yates and associates, Europe's Needs and Resources (New York and London: Twentieth Century Fund and MacMillan & Co., 1961), ? published or unpublished? (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Review of J. L. Meij, Mechanization in Agriculture (Amsterdam, Chicago: North Holland Publishing Company, Quadrangle Books Inc., 1960), ? published or unpublished?, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Review of Georg Siemens, History of the House of Siemens (Kreiburg/Munich: Karl Aber, 1957), The Journal of Economic History. Vol. XXI, No. 1, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Review of Wilhem Krelle, Volkwirtschaftliche Gesamtrechnung (Berlin Dunker & Humbolt, 1959), Econometrica. Vol. 29, No 2, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Review of Conrad Reuss, Emile Koutny and Leon Tychon, Le Progrés Économique en Sidérurgie: Belgique, Luxembourg, Pay-Bas, 1830-1955 (Louvain, Germany: Editions Nauwelaerts, 1960), The Journal of Economic History. Vol XXII, No. 1, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Review of W. O. Henderson, The Industrial Revolution in Europe, 1815-1914 (Chicago: Quadrangle Books, 1962), The Journal of Political Economy. Vol LXXI, No. 5, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Review of H. J. Habakkuk, American and British Technology in the Nineteenth Century (Cambridge, England: Cambridge University Press, 1962), The Business History Review. Vol XXXVII, No. 1-2, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Review of Allan G. Bogue, From Prairie to Corn Belt: Farming on the Illinois and Iowa Prairies in the Nineteenth Century (Chicago: The University of Chicago Press, 1963), Business History Review. Vol. XXXVIII, No. 3, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Review of Eric E. Lampard, The Rise of the Dairy Industry in Wisconsin: A Study in Agricultural Change (Madison: The State Historical Society of Wisconsin, 1963), Business History Review. Vol. XXXVIII, No. 3, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Review of Barry E. Supple, The Experience of Economic Growth: Case Studies in Economic History (New York: Random House, 1963), The J ournal of Economic History. Vol. XXIV, No. 2, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Review of G. E. Mingay, English Landed Society in the Eighteenth Century (London and Toronto: Routledge and Kegan Paul, University of Toronto Press, 1963), The Journal of Economic History. Vol. XXV, No. 2, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Review of F. M. L. Thompson, English Landed Society in the Eighteenth Century (London and Toronto: Routledge and Kegan Paul, University of Toronto Press, 1963), The Journal of Economic History. Vol. XXV, No. 2, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Cambridge Economic History, Volume VI: The Industrial Revolutions and After (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1966), The Journal of Economic History. Vol. XXVI, No. 1 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Review of Eugene D. Genovese, The Political Economy of Slavery, Studies in the Economy and Society of the Slave South (New York: Pantheon Press, 1964), The Economic History Review. Second Series, Vol. XX, No. 1, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Review of Peter Temin, Iron and Steel in the Nineteenth Century: An Economic Inquiry (Cambridge, Mass: M.I.T. Press, 1964), The Journal of Political Econom y. Vol. 75, No. 1, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Review of Simon Kuznets, Modern Economic Growth: Rate, Structure and Spread (New Haven and London: Yale University Press, 1966), Review of Income and Wealth. Series 13, No. 2, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Review of Harold D. Woodman, King Cotton and His Retainers: Financing and Marketing the Cotton Crop of the South, 1800-1925 (Lexington, Kentucky: University of Kentucky Press,), The Journal of Economic History. Vol. XXVIII, No. 4, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Review of John Hicks, A Theory of Economic History (New York: Oxford University Press, 1969), The American Historical Review. Vol. 77, No. 4, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Review of Jonathan Hughes, Industrialization and Economic History: Theses and Conjectures (New York: McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1970), The American Historical Review. Vol. 77, No. 4, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Review of Thomas C. Cochran, Business in American Life: A History (New York: McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1972), The American Historical Review. Vol 798, No. 2, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Review of Nathan Rosenberg, Technology and American Economic Growth (New York: Harper & Row, 1972), The Journal of American History, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Review of William O. Aydelotte, Allan G. Bogue, and Robert Wiliam Fogel, The Dimensions of Quantitative Research in History (Princeton, N.J.: Princeton University Press, 1972), Journal of Economic Literature. Vol XII: 6, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Review of Val R. Lorwin and Jacob M. Price, The Dimensions of the Past: Materials, Problems, and Opportunities for Quantitative Work in History (New Haven and London: Yale University Press, 1972), Journal of Economic Literature. Vol XII, No. 6, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Review of Robert Fogel and Stanley Engerman, Time on the Cross (Boston: Little, Brown, 1974), Reviews in American History. Vol. 2, No. 4 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Review of J.D. Gould, Economic Growth in History: Survey and Analysis (London: Methuen: Barnes and Noble, New York, 1972), American Historical Review. Vol. 79, No. 1, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Review of Margaret Walsh, The Manufacturing Frontier, Pioneer Industry in Antebellum Wisconsin 1830-1860 (Madison, Wisconsin: State Historical Society of Wisconsin, 1972), Economica. Vol. 41, No. 161, (1974) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Review of Lee Soltow, Men and Wealth in the United States 1850-1870 (New Haven and London: Yale University Press, 1975), Journal of Interdisciplinary History. Vol IV, No. 3, (1974) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Review of Lee Soltow, Patterns of Wealthholding in Wisconsin since 1850 (Madison: University of Wisconsin Press, 1970), Journal of Interdisciplinary History. Vol IV: 3, (1974) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Review of William Woodruff, America's Impact on the World (London and New York: Macmillan Press and Halstead Press (John Wiley), 1975), Journal of Economic History. XXXV (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Review of Paul A. David, Technological Choice, Innovation and Economic Growth: Essays on American and British Experience in the Nineteenth Century (New York and London: Cambridge University Press, 1975), Agricultural History, (1976) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Review of Andre Gunder Frank, World Accumulation, 1492-1789 (London and New York: Monthly Review Press, 1978), Journal of Economic History (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Review of John D. Post, The Last Great Subsistence Crisis in the Western World (Baltimore: The Johns Hopkins University Press, 1977), Agricultural History. 52, (1978) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Review of David Spring, European Lanced Elites in the Nineteenth Century (Baltimore and London: The Johns Hopkins University Press, 1977), Journal of Economic History. XXXVIII, (1978) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Review of A. Milward and S. B. Saul, The Development of the Economies of Continental Europe, 1850-1914 (London and Cambridge, Mass.: G. Allen and Unwin and Harvard University Press, 1977), Journal of Economic History. Vol. 38, No. 3, (1978) (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Review of Oscar Handlin, Truth in History (Cambridge, Mass.: The Belknap Press of the Harvard University Press, 1979), ? published or unpublished? (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Review of Walt W. Rostow, The World Economy: History and Prospec t (Austin and London: University of Texas Press, 1978), Journal of Economic History, (1979) (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Review of Suzanne Berger, Organizing Interests in Western Europe- Pluralism, Corporatism and the Transformation of Politics (New York: Cambridge University Press, 1981). Journal of Economic History. XLIII No.3, (1983) (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Review of P.D. Anthony, John Ruskin's labour. A study of Ruskin's social theory (Cambridge, NY and Sydney: Cambridge University Press, 1983), Journal of Economic Literature. XXIII, (1985) (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Review of Steven Hahn and Jonathan Prude, The Countryside in the Age of Capitalist Transformation: Essays in the Social History of Rural America. (Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press, 1985), Journal of Economic History, (1986) (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Review of Joel Mokyr, The Economics of the Industrial Revolution (Totowa, N.J.: Rowman & Allanheld, Publishers, 1985), Albion. Vol. 18, No. 2, (1986) (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Review of Ross Thomson, The Birth of Mechanized Production in the United States, unpublished, (1987) (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Review of Fernand Braudel, C ivilization and Capitalism, 15th-18th Century. Volume 3: The Perspective of the World. (New York: Harper & Row, 1984), Business History Review. Vol. 61, Autumn, (1987) (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Review of Donald C. Coleman and Peter Mathias, Enterprise and History: Essays in Honour of Charles Wilson. (New York: Cambridge University Press, 1984), J ournal of Interdisciplinary History. XVII No.3, (1987) (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Review of Stanley Engerman and Robert E. Gallman, Long Term Trends in American Economic Growth eds., (Chicago: The University of Chicago Press, 1986) Journal of Economic History, (1988) (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Review of Donald N. McCloskey, Econometric History (London: Macmillan, for the Economic History Society, 1987), Journal of Economic History, (1989) (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Review of Ravi Batra, Regular Economic Cycles: Money, Inflation, Regulation, and Depressions (New York: St. Martin's Press), New York Times Book Review. Oct, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Review of George J. Stigler, Memoirs of an Unregulated Economist (New York: Basic Books, 1988), Journal of Economic Literature. Vol 27, December, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Review of Alfred D. Chandler, Jr., Scale and Scope: The Dynamics of Industrial Capitalism (Cambridge and London: The Belknap Press of Harvard University Press, 1990), Journal of Economic History. vol. 51, no. 4, (1991) (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Review of N. J. G. Pounds, An Historical Geography of Europe (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1990), Journal of Historical Geography. vol. ?, (1992) (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Review of Gerold Ambrosius & William H. Hubbard, A Social and Economic History of Twentieth-Century Europe (Cambridge Mass.: Harvard University Press, 1989), History of European Ideas. XIV, (1992) (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Review of Patrick Higonnet, David Landes, & Henry Rosovsky, eds., Favorites of Fortune: Technology, Growth, and Economic Development Since the Industrial Revolution (Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press, 1991) Journal of Political Economy, (1992) (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Additional Material, 1935-1946, undated; Accession 1994-M-016; 0.5; (1 box)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1994 Mar
  Received from: William N. Parker, 1993 Aug 25
  - Atomic Energy Act of 1946 (Senate bill 1717)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1946; undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Remarks on S.1717: incomplete draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Senate hearings on S.1717: printed material, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Senate hearings on S. Res. 179: printed material, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Atomic energy: general information, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Harvard papers: English themes, 1935-1938, undated (Box 1, Folder 7-11)
  - Writings, 1939-1940 undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Additional Material, 1950s-1980s; Accession 1995-M-104; 2 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1995 Feb
  Received from: William N. Parker. 1995 Jan 25
  These course materials were refoldered using original folder titles and maintaining original arrangement.
  - Course outlines, reading lists, etc. (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Econ 130 lectures: modern economic history (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Introduction to European economic history (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Primitive economics (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - European economic history: overview (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - LSE lecture notes (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Maps, diagrams, tables, graphs, etc. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Nussdorfer research notes (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Econ 580b: schemata (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Social classes (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Europe: pre-history to B.C. 500 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Greece and Rome (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Mediterranean economy, 1100-1600 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Dutch, Northern Europe, 1550-1700 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Price revolution of 16th and 17th centuries (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Agrarian organization (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Population (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Agriculture/productivity (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Trade: real factors early, modern (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Growth of trade: processes (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Credit and finance: private and public (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Industrial Revolution: technology (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Industrial Revolution: location (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Industrial Revolution: effects (Box 1, Folder 28)